A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, General Correspondence FA735
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, General Correspondence
1951-1970
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA735
669 microform reels
The Ford Foundation's General Correspondence files for the years 1951-1970 are housed on 669 reels of microfilm and number sequentially from C-1138 to C-1806, including two 'A' numbered reels. General Correspondence Files for 1951 - 1960 are housed on 280 reels of 35mm microfilm, and numbered C-1138 thru C-1416 (including two 'A' numbered reels), while the files for 1961 - 1970 are housed on 389 reels of 16mm microfilm, and numbered C-1417 thru C-1806.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement note
Ford Foundation General Correspondence Files for 1951-1964 are arranged by year, then alphabetically by file heading.
General Correspondence Files for the years 1965-1970 are arranged by year, then by the Foundation's Division/Program, and alphabetically by file heading within the Division/Program.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Other Finding Aids note
General Correspondence Files for 1951-1970 are indexed by the Ford Foundation's Central Index cards, 1950-1975 (FA736). However, the index cards are no longer an accurate index of the General Correspondence files on microfilm, as these files were "weeded" prior to microfilming. It appears the index cards were not updated to reflect the destroyed correspondence.
The Central Index cards do provide indexing for correspondence after 1970, but these files are not housed in the General Correspondence Files. Correspondence indexed as "Gen 71…" or later might be found in the departmental Program/Division collections of correspondence, which are including in the individual 'Office Files' collections.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: correspondence.
- General Correspondence, 1951
  - A - AZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1138)
  - Adler, Mortimer J., 1951 (Reel C-1138)
  - American Association of the Advancement of Science, 1951 (Reel C-1138)
  - American Cancer Society, 1951 (Reel C-1138)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1951 (Reel C-1138)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1951 (Reel C-1138)
  - American Red Cross, 1951 (Reel C-1138)
  - Area I (Peace), 1951 (Reel C-1138)
  - Area II (Democracy), 1951 (Reel C-1138)
  - Area III (Economic Development), 1951 (Reel C-1138)
  - Area V (Behavioral Sciences), 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Asia, 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Attorney Generals List of Subversive Organizations, 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - BA - BZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Benton, Senator William, 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Bissell, Richard M., Jr., 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Blakely, R.J., 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Breakneck Hill Conference, 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - CA - CZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - CARE, 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Carnegie Foundation and Corporation, 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Clark, Glenn, 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Commission on International Cooperation in Education, 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Compton, Karl T., 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Congressional Luncheon, 1951 (Reel C-1139)
  - Conservation, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Cowles, John, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - DA - DZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - David, Donald K., 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Davis, Chester C., 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - De Diego, Julio, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - EA - EZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Economic Cooperation Administration, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Ensminger, Douglas, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Exchange of Persons, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - FA - FZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Far East, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Faust, Dr. Clarence H., 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Ferry, W. H., 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Fletcher, Scott C., 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Ford Motor Company, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Foundations, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Fox, Melvin, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Freedom and Civil Liberties Seminar, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Fund for Advancement of Education, 1951 (Reel C-1140)
  - Fund for Adult Education, 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - GA - GZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - Gaither, H. Rowan, Jr., 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - Germany, 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - Gladieux, Bernard C., 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - Goldwyn, Samuel, 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - HA - HZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - Hoffman, Paul G., 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - Holmes, Horace, 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - Howard, John B., 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - Hutchins, Robert M., 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - IA - IZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - Illinois Institute of Technology, 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - India, 1951 (Reel C-1141)
  - Indonesia, 1951 (Reel C-1142)
  - Institute of International Education, 1951 (Reel C-1142)
  - Iverson, Kenneth, 1951 (Reel C-1142)
  - JA - JZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1142)
  - KA - KZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1142)
  - Katz, Milton, 1951 (Reel C-1142)
  - Kennan, George F., 1951 (Reel C-1142)
  - LA - LZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1142)
  - Libya, 1951 (Reel C-1142)
  - MA - MZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1142)
  - Malik, Charles, Dr., 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Marquis, Donald G., 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - May, Oliver, 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - McDaniel, Joseph M. Jr., 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Meyer, Mr. Eugene (Agnes), 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Moyer, Raymond T., 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - NA - NZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - National, 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Near East, 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Near East and Asia Proposals, 1951 (Reel C-1143)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes material thru November 3, 1951.
  - Newsome, Earl & Co., 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - OA - OZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Office of Education, 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Overseas Development, 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Overseas Training of Specialists, 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - PA - PZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Pakistan, 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Palestine Refugee Program, 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Pasadena Chamber of Commerce, 1951 (Reel C-1143)
  - Peace Seminar, May 28, 29, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Population, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Press Information Service, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Project Information, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Project Information, Sept. 1, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Public Administration Clearing House, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Publications, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - RA - RZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Race Relations, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Refugees, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Rehabilitation, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Rockefeller, John D. III, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - SA - SZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1144)
  - Salomon, Colonel Irving, 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - Spaeth, Carl, 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - State Department, 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - Stevens, Sir Bertram, 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - TA - TZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - Teague, Walter Dorwin, 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - Telephone Service, 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - Teletype, 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - Television, 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - Tilney, John, 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - Tolley, Howard R., 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - Travel, 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - UA - UZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1145)
  - UNESCO, 1951 (Reel C-1145, Reel C-1146)
  - United Nations, 1951 (Reel C-1146)
  - VA - VZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1146)
  - Vogt, William, 1951 (Reel C-1146)
  - WA - WZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1146)
  - World Land Tenure Problems, 1951 (Reel C-1146)
  - YA - YZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1146)
  - Young, James W., 1951 (Reel C-1146)
  - Yugoslavia, 1951 (Reel C-1146)
  - ZA - ZZ [General File], 1951 (Reel C-1146)
- General Correspondence, 1952
  - AA - AZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1146)
  - Abrams, Frank, 1952 (Reel C-1146)
  - Adler, Mortimer, 1952 (Reel C-1146)
  - Africa, 1952 (Reel C-1146)
  - Africa Conference, 1952 (Reel C-1146)
  - Albright, Horace, 1952 (Reel C-1146)
  - American (General), 1952 (Reel C-1146)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1952 (Reel C-1147)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1952 (Reel C-1147)
  - American Council on Education, 1952 (Reel C-1147)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS), 1952 (Reel C-1147)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1952 (Reel C-1147)
  - American Political Science Association, 1952 (Reel C-1147)
  - American Red Cross, 1952 (Reel C-1147)
  - Angelo, Homer, 1952 (Reel C-1147)
  - Area I (Peace), 1952 (Reel C-1147)
  - Area II (Democracy), 1952 (Reel C-1147)
  - Area III (Economic Development), 1952 (Reel C-1147)
  - Area V (Behavioral Sciences), 1952 (Reel C-1147, Reel C-1148)
  - Arnold, Edwin, 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - Asia, 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - Association of Land Grant Colleges and Universities, 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - BA - BZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - Benton, Senator William, 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - Berelson, Bernard, 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - Bissell, Richard M. Jr., 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - Board on Overseas Training and Research (BOTR), 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - Bowles, Chester, 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - Brown, Dyke, 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - Burma, 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - Burma, 1952 (Reel C-1148)
    Includes "Mr. Arnold's background material".
  - CA - CZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1148)
  - CA - CZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - California State Board of Corrections, 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Calkins, Robert, 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Carroll, Thomas H., 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Center for International Studies (M.I.T., Max F. Milliken), 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Checch, Vincent, 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Community Chest Campaign, 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Condliffe, John B. (Professor, University of California), 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Condon, Edward J., 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Conservation, 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Coombs, Philip H., 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Corson, John J., 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, Inc., 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Cowles, John, 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - Cox Committee, 1952 (Reel C-1149)
  - DA - DZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Darr, John W., 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Daugherty, Carroll R., 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Davenport, Russell, 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - David, Donald K., 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - David, Paul T., 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Davis, Chester, 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - De Schweinitz, Karl (Prof.), 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Disarmament, 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - EA - EZ, 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Education, 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Egypt, 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Eliot, Charles W., 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Ensminger, Douglas, 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Europe, 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Everton, John, 1952 (Reel C-1150)
  - Exchange of Persons, 1952 (Reel C-1150, Reel C-1151)
  - FA - FZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Fairbank, John K., 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Ferry, W. H., 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Fisher, Arthur, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Flandes, Ralph E., 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Ford, Benson, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Ford, Henry II, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Ford Motor Company, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Ford Motor Company Fund, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Forkner, Claude E., 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Foundations - General, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Fox, Melvin, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Fund for Adult Education, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - GA - GZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Gaither, H. Rowan, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Germany, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Gladieux, Bernard L., 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Gordon, Stanley T., 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Governor's Conference on Educational Television, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Gustavson, R.G., 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - HA - HZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Haskins, Caryl, 1952 (Reel C-1151)
  - Heard, Alexander, 1952 (Reel C-1151, Reel C-1152)
  - Hoffman, Paul G., 1952 (Reel C-1152)
  - Howard, John, 1952 (Reel C-1152)
  - Hunting, Willis B., 1952 (Reel C-1152)
  - Hutchins, Robert M., 1952 (Reel C-1152)
  - IA - IZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1152)
  - Illum, Knud, 1952 (Reel C-1152)
  - India, 1952 (Reel C-1152)
  - Indochina, 1952 (Reel C-1152)
  - Indonesia - Burma Report/Appendices 1-20, 1952 (Reel C-1152)
  - Indonesia, 1952 (Reel C-1152)
  - Institute of International Education, 1952 (Reel C-1152, Reel C-1153)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, Inc. - American, 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences, 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - International Conference in Agriculture and Cooperative Credit, University of California, Berkeley, 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - International..., 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - Iran, 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - Iraq, 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - Israel, 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - Italy, 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - Iverson, Kenneth R., 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - JA - JZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - Jackson College, 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - Japan (Status Report), 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - Japan, 1952 (Reel C-1153)
  - Jordan, 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - KA - KZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - Katz, Milton, 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - Kennan, George, 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - Klemme, Randall T., 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - LA - LZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - Land Reform, 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - Laves, Walter, H.C., 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - Lenhart, Robert F., 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - Lewis, Oscar, 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - Likert, Rensis, 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - MA - MZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - Mutual Security Agency, 1952 (Reel C-1154)
  - NA - NZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Naidis, Mark, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - National Committee for a Free Europe, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - National Planning Association, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - National Research Council, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Near East, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Near East Foundation, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Neill, George W., 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Newsom, Earl + Company, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Nielsen, Waldemar A., 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Nigeria, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Novins, Louis A., 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - OA - OZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Oliver, Corey T., 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Overseas - Ad Hoc Committee for Training and Research, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Overseas Development, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Overseas Division - Weekly Reports, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - PA - PZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Pakistan, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Palestine, 1952 (Reel C-1155)
  - Paley Commission (Materials Policy Commission), 1952 (Reel C-1155, Reel C-1156)
  - Peace, 1952 (Reel C-1156)
  - Philippine Islands, 1952 (Reel C-1156)
  - Population, 1952 (Reel C-1156)
  - Public Administration Clearing House, 1952 (Reel C-1156)
  - RA - RZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1156)
  - Redfield, Robert, 1952 (Reel C-1156)
  - Refugees, 1952 (Reel C-1156)
  - SA - SZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Sayre, Wallace, 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Schuster, George N., 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Spaeth, Carl, 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - State Department, 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Stauffer, Tom, 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Stead, William H., 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Stevens, Harley C., 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Stone, Donald C., 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Supomo, R., 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Syria, 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - TA - TZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Taylor, George E., 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Technical Assistance, 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Technical Assistance Board, 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Technical Cooperation Admin., 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Thurber, Clarence, 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Tolley, Howard R., 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Travel, 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Turkey, 1952 (Reel C-1157)
  - Turner, E. Stanton, 1952 (Reel C-1157, Reel C-1158)
  - United Nations, 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - UNESCO, 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - Vogt, William, 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - WA - WZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - Wallace, Schuyler G., 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - Webber, James B. Jr., 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - Wilkin, Robert N., 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - Williamsburg, Virginia - Conference on Population Problems, 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - Wilson, Charles E., 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - Wilson, Milburn L., 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - World Brotherhood, 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - Wyzanski, Charles E. Jr., 1952 (Reel C-1158)
  - YA - YZ [General File], 1952 (Reel C-1158)
- General Correspondence, 1953
  - AA - AZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - Advertising Council, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - Africa, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - Aikin, Charles, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - Allen, F. Lewis, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - Allman, Norwood F., 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - American..., 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - American council on Education, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - American Friends of the Middle East, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - American Red Cross, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - Angelo, Homer, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - Appleby, Paul, 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - Area I (Peace), 1953 (Reel C-1159)
  - Area I (Peace) - Draft Discussion Documents, 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Area I (Peace) - Program for Asia and the Near East, 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Area II (Democracy), 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Area III (Economic Development), 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Area IV (Education), 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Area V (Behavioral Sciences), 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Area V (Behavioral Sciences) - Ford Foundation Behavioral Science Division Report, June 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Armour Research Foundation, 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Asia, 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - BA - BZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Beirut Conference of Overseas Representatives, 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Bissell, Richard, 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Board on Overseas Training and Research (BOTR), 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Board on Overseas Training and Research (BOTR) Fellowships - Recruitment, 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Bower, Robert T., 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Bower, John Z., 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Brown, Courtney, 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Brown, Dyke, 1953 (Reel C-1160)
  - Brown, William O., 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Brownlee, James, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Burma, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - CA - CZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Carroll, Thomas H., 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Casey, Richard, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Chambers, J.M., 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Chen, Kuo-Lien, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - China, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Cole, Charles W., 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Commerce Department, U.S., 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Committee for a Free Asia, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Condliffe, J.B., 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Conservation Foundation, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Coombs, Philip, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Corker, Charles E., 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Cowles, John, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Cox Committee, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - DA - DZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - Davis, Chester, 1953 (Reel C-1161)
  - EA - EZ, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Education, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Egger, Rowland, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Egypt, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Eliot, Charles W., 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Ensminger, Douglas, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Exchange of Persons, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Exchange of Persons Projects (Summary Reports), 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - FA - FZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Federal Security Agency, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Finnish Foreign Trade Association, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Fletcher, C. Scott, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO), 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Ford, Benson, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Ford, Henry II, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Freeman, Frank N., 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Fund for Adult Education - Meetings of Jan. 23-24, May 28-29, and Oct. 21, 1953 (Reel C-1162)
  - Fund for Adult Education (Programs), 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Foreign Operations Administration, 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Foundations, General, 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - GA - GZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Gaither, H. Rowan, 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Gladieux, Bernard L., 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - HA - HZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Harbison, Frederick H., 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Hoffman, Paul G., 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Hutchins, Robert M., 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Huth, Arno G., 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - IA - IZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Illinois Institute of Technology, 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - India, 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Indochina, 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Indonesia, 1953 (Reel C-1163)
  - Institute of International Education (May - August), 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Institute of International Education (Sept - December), 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Institute of International Education (Jan. - April), 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Inter-American Press Association, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - International, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Iran, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Iraq, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Israel, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Iverson, Kenneth R., 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - JA - JZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Japan, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Jessup, Phillip, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Johnson, V. Webster, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Jordan, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - KA - KZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Kaiser, Philip M., 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Katz, Milton, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Kidd, Philip C., 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Klemme, Randall T., 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - LA - LZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Land Reform, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Langer, Paul, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Latin America, 1953 (Reel C-1164)
  - Laughlin, J., 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Lebanon, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Leenhouts, Grant, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Lockwood, William W., 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - MA - MZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - McDaniel, Joseph, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - McPeak, William, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Malik, Charles, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Maris, Paul, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Millikan, Max F., 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Moyer, Raymond T., 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - NA - NZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - National, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - National Planning Association, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Near East, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Nielsen, Waldemar A., 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - OA - OZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Overseas, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Overseas Division Staff Meetings, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Overseas Representatives Conference, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - PA - PZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Pakistan, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Philippine Islands, 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Population - Report & Appendices "The Physiological Approach to Fertility Control", 1953 (Reel C-1165)
  - Population, 1953 (Reel C-1165A)
    Scope and Contents note
    16mm reel
  - Point IV (Point Four), 1953 (Reel C-1166)
  - Price, Donald K., 1953 (Reel C-1166)
  - Princeton University, 1953 (Reel C-1166)
  - Public Administration Clearing House, 1953 (Reel C-1166)
  - RA - RZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1166)
  - Refugees, 1953 (Reel C-1166)
  - Research, 1953 (Reel C-1166)
  - SA - SZ [General File], 1953 (Reel C-1166)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1953 (Reel C-1166)
  - Soil Conservation Policy Conference, 1953 (Reel C-1166)
  - South Africa, 1953 (Reel C-1166)
  - Soviet Studies Conference, 1953 October 9-10 (Reel C-1166)